<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>compphys on Knowledge x Base</title>
    <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/tags/compphys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in compphys on Knowledge x Base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>© me</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 14:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hhn-pham.github.io/tags/compphys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pointers</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/pointers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/pointers/</guid>
      <description>Definition  define an integer and reserves a location in memory for this specific variable  take an integer pointer:    int *pointer  this defines an integer pointer such that its content is the address of another place in memory  int var var = 10 pointer = &amp;amp;var  this defines an integer var, and &amp;amp;var is the address of a specific place in memory where the integer is stored  it also points the variable pointer to var   so that when checking out the value *pointer*, we get the content of var, which is 10  With arrays  pointers can also be appointed to arrays so that using (pointer + 1) points to certain array element matr[1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round-off errors</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/round-off-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/round-off-errors/</guid>
      <description>Page 27, paragraph 2, line 8-17  Since e^-20^ is a very small number and each term in the series can be rather large (of the order of 10^8^,it is clear that other terms as large as 10^8^, but negative, must cancel the figures in front of the decimal point and some behind as well. Since a computer can only hold a fixed number of significant figures, all those in front of the decimal point are not only useless, they are crowding out needed figures at the right end of the number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The loss-of-precision theorem</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/the-loss-of-precision-theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/the-loss-of-precision-theorem/</guid>
      <description>Subtraction If b and c are positive normalized floating-point binary machine numbers with $b &amp;lt; c$ and
$$ 2^{-r} \leq 1 - \frac{c}{b} \leq 2^{-s}, $$
Then at most $r$ and at least $s$ significant binary bits are lost in the subtraction $b-c$.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
