<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tech on Organisation x Knowledge Base</title>
    <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tech on Organisation x Knowledge Base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>© me</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 17:43:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hhn-pham.github.io/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 17:43:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/hugo/</guid>
      <description>Difficulties using themes So far, my experience with Hu(go) has been alright. I found a nice theme called &amp;ldquo;cactus&amp;rdquo;, and while it worked when served locally for testing, it did not work when deployed (even just testing it locally by opening index.html), the css files were getting sourced and everything, but the website would not render any css. I found opened issues on Github saying that neither the css nor the html templates are valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Vimwiki to plain Markdown</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/from-vimwiki-to-plain-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 21:47:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/from-vimwiki-to-plain-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Why I&amp;rsquo;m changing I have been using a combination of vimwiki and Mkdocs inside neovim for a while now, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really satisified with the outcome. Although Mkdocs with the material theme is extremely feature-packed (python markdown extensions are really good), I feel like rejecting bloat and returning to simplicity is better for blogging/journalling/organising in general. Mkdocs was made with slick documentions in mind so the javascript was annoying me quite a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dotfiles</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/dotfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/dotfiles/</guid>
      <description>Dotfiles This a write-up for the README.md file for my dotfiles repository so the links will not work.
Programs and tools    Program Name     Shell ZSH   Editor Neovim   Window manager i3-gaps   Compositor Picom   Bar Polybar   Launcher rofi   Browser Brave   Audio Pipewire   Spotify ncspot   PDF viewer Zathura   Media player MPV   GTK &amp;amp; colors wpgtk   Colorscheme Custom   Fetch neofetch   Prompt Spaceship   Terminal Kitty   Icons Fluent dark   Cursor Bibata   Lock i3-lock   Display manager LightDM   LightDM theme Aether   Notifications i3-notifier   Downloads Aria2   Image viewer feh    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from yay to paru</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/paru/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 21:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/paru/</guid>
      <description>Migration Moving from yay to paru, I discovered a few useful commands that existed in yay that I never bothered checking out.
Cheatsheet Below is a snippet from my zshrc showing my paru aliases and their tldr:
alias pu=&amp;#39;paru -Syu&amp;#39; #sync &amp;amp; upgrade alias pusu=&amp;#39;paru -Syu --noconfirm&amp;#39; #sync &amp;amp; upgrade w/o confirmation alias pfetch=&amp;#39;paru -Ps&amp;#39; #display stats alias pcom=&amp;#39;paru -Gc&amp;#39; #display comments alias pnews=&amp;#39;paru -Pw&amp;#39; #display news alias pid=&amp;#39;paru -U&amp;#39; #install from local file(s) alias pir=&amp;#39;paru -S&amp;#39; #install from repositories alias pnd=&amp;#39;paru -Qi&amp;#39; #display info from database alias pnr=&amp;#39;paru -Si&amp;#39; #display info from repositories alias pfd=&amp;#39;paru -Qs&amp;#39; #search in database alias pfr=&amp;#39;paru -Ss&amp;#39; #search in repositories alias pls=&amp;#39;paru -Q&amp;#39; #list packages installed alias plsa=&amp;#39;paru -Qea&amp;#39; #list packages explicitly installed alias porf=&amp;#39;paru -Qdt&amp;#39; #list orphaned packages alias pcc=&amp;#39;paru -Scd&amp;#39; #interactive cache removal FZF integration I also found that defining an installing and removing function which uses FZF to crawl through the local database is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash scripting</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/bash-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/bash-scripting/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I wanted a simple and creative way to manage my dotfiles, one which would allow more automation than my previous method. I stumbled upon many existing tools that can be utilised to manage dotfiles, such as GNU Stow and chezmoi. But they all seem to be too overkill for me, and their management method do not float my boat quite that well. Here&amp;rsquo;s what these tools might envision a ~/dotfiles or ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>/etc/hosts</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/hostfile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/hostfile/</guid>
      <description>Utility I am now using hblock and it seems to be really great at managing /etc/hosts. To put simply, I have a template with my hostname and localhost, and then a sources.list file with StevenBlack master hostfile. Hblock essentially appends the StevenBlack&amp;rsquo;s hostfile to the template and then move it to /etc/hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Neo)vim</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 16:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/vim/</guid>
      <description>Experience I wanted to make a custom cheatsheet with all my custom bindings, (update 24/08: after constantly forcing myself to look up ways to do things without just going jjj or kkkk or whatever repetitive motions you would normally do, I&amp;rsquo;m a much better vim user now)
I assigned ; to : a while ago, but I moved to &amp;lt;space&amp;gt;. While it&amp;rsquo;s been hard to change my muscle memory, it means since my leader key is ,, I can have the sequence comma+semicolon executing &amp;lt;esc&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chat services</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/chat-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/chat-services/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a qualm: there are simply too many chat services, it&amp;rsquo;s splitting my brain
 discord as primary communication with my boyfriend, some of my friends, and most of popular public servers  discord + e2ee @ browser for main discord &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; insular @ android for main discord electron + betterdiscord integrations @ linux for alt, only for calling my boyfriend   telegram with my parents &amp;amp; lingering privacy-centric groups, or android modding groups  nekogram x @ android telegram k web @ browser   matrix (with libera bridge) for most public groups that are worthy enough to use the protocol, mainly privacy-focussed group and tech-related  fluffychat @ android mirage @ linux   whatsapp for absolute normies (uni groups, housemates, most irl boomers)  whatsapp &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; insular @ android whatsapp web @ browser but cookies are not saved   messenger/facebook/instagram for some old friends, but I probably open those websites once a year at this point  barinsta &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; insular @ android with chat function web versions @ browser but again, I simply avoid using it    Internet guide I followed this link below to integrate libera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TTRSS</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/ttrss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 17:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/ttrss/</guid>
      <description>Local-hosting So I&amp;rsquo;m hosting a Tiny Tiny RSS locally (LAN-only) and it works great, the web-ui is so damn slick with awesome-ttrss
On the phone I am using the default app on f-droid and although there is no inline reading mode, it still works pretty well, all articles will have to be saved offline once I leave my house
To get it running on my box: cd $HOME/docker/rss docker-compose up -d </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitwarden</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/bitwarden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 03:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/bitwarden/</guid>
      <description>Self-hosting  I sucesfully setup a docker container that is self-hosting bitwarden locally. I cannot expose the server so locally should be ideal still since I&amp;rsquo;m not going out as much or doing anything which requires instantaneous syncing. my passwords now contain a single point of failure, and that is my physical computer, if anything were to happen to the data on my nvme, then my passwords are screwed but hey, at least my passwords are not lingering somewhere on a centralised server that is very attractive to those with malicious intents I&amp;rsquo;m not important anyway, who would want to attack my local data?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 02:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Content  reddit mastodon lemmy hacker news  Cloud  mega nextcloud github  Utilities  syncthing nextdns anonaddy custom rom  Messaging  whatsapp telegram discord matrix  Media  predb snahp last.fm  youtube  Inboxes  protonmail disroot outlook uni gmail  Read later  consciousness &amp;amp; qp intro to dl bell&amp;rsquo;s theorem homunculus  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luks on LVM</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/luksonlvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 01:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/posts/luksonlvm/</guid>
      <description>LUKS setup I wanted to protect my desktop PC with LUKS2, I decided to use LVM after reading not so good things about BTRFS. I settled on LUKS on LVM instead of LVM on LUKS because I wanted to have partition separation for easier control if I do end up with a corrupted root partition. While chain unlocking is not as secure as entering two passwords to decrypt two partitions, the guide I used worked and it is a very good guide which explains everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital tasks</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/digital-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 06:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/digital-tasks/</guid>
      <description>Arch fix it before you reinstall
 get a Windows VM going (bonus if I can achieve GPU passthrough) rofi emoji switcher is it possible to rice systemd-boot? the answer is no 😥 neovim needs more of your attention background manga setup with hakuneko + zathura or mangodl with ranger backup files on the hard disk and make it btrfs! updated: no, going with ext4 vimwiki as git home zathura rice discord rice spotify rice migrate from wal to wpgtk i3 stuff:  i3-notifier i3-resurrect i3-bar as a hidden status line make a theme randomizer/chooser with rofi make a rofi cheatsheet (I&amp;rsquo;m too alpha for this) floating vim everywhere 😵 thread   configure broot transfer dotfiles to one folder and symlink everything git dotfiles + reddit post?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
