<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Knowledge x Base</title>
    <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Knowledge x Base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>© me</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 20:17:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hhn-pham.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Realism and Anti-Realism</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/realism-antirealism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 20:17:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/realism-antirealism/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction Notes 1:2  Aim of this book:  To make clear what is really at stake in the contemporary realism debate Claim: no other book has succeeded in doing that Being more accessible than other books by containing less philosophical jargon    2:1  Definition of realism:  Realism about a particular domain is the conjunction (x and y) of the theses:  (i) the existence thesis: there are facts or entities distinctive of that domain (ii) the independence thesis: their existence and nature is in some important sense objective and mind-independent      2:2  Existence thesis (elaboration):  Caveat: involves quantification over entities and facts  Entities: referents of singular terms Facts: aspects of the world represented by whole declarative sentences Those who distinguished existence and independence thesis only quantified it over individuals Q: why is the involvement of both facts and entities awkward?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute space</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/absolute-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/notes/absolute-space/</guid>
      <description>The Cartesian body  motion of a body is a change of relation to the bodies that surround it. concept of inertia  a body&amp;rsquo;s motion will be preserved unless caused to deviate from its path so not a function of its spatial relations to other bodies but of its causal relation    The Newtonian body  a body&amp;rsquo;s motion is not a function of its spatial relations to other objects but rather of whether forces are impressed on it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
