<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orgs on Organisation x Knowledge Base</title>
    <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Orgs on Organisation x Knowledge Base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>© me</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 02:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 02:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Content  reddit mastodon lemmy hacker news rss  Cloud  mega nextcloud github  Utilities  syncthing nextdns anonaddy custom rom  Messaging  whatsapp telegram discord matrix  Media  predb snahp last.fm  youtube  Inboxes  protonmail disroot outlook uni gmail  Read later  consciousness &amp;amp; qp intro to dl bell&amp;rsquo;s theorem homunculus  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groceries</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/groceries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 01:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/groceries/</guid>
      <description>Things to buy  rice soy sauce lentils cereal dishwashing liquid a stock pot a small baking tray eggs butter pierogi soy sauce/that thing ketchup milk cheese bread potatoes deodorant eggs cereal muesli meatballs pasta condiments pasta (farfalle) pasta sauce (pesto) rice chickpeas cereal milk block of cheddar &amp;amp; ricotto ice cream broccy tomatoes bananas yoghurt? milk cereal (for him and for her) parmesan bread cream cheese soy sauce soyjacks bananas cocoa smol rice 1kg et Al jogury cereal milk potatoes onion tuna some kind of meat cheese snackies  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 01:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/agenda/</guid>
      <description>2021    Date Event     22 Jul Result day   25 Jul Bebe   06 Aug Rent due   25 Aug Southville rent due   01 Sep southville tenancy starts   04 Sep 2nd dose   05 Sep UWE tenancy ends    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal tasks</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/personal-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/personal-tasks/</guid>
      <description>24-07  buy bus ticket 🚌 buy groceries 🍉 clothes  dress shorts shirts    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital tasks</title>
      <link>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/digital-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 06:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hhn-pham.github.io/org/digital-tasks/</guid>
      <description>Arch fix it before you reinstall
 get a Windows VM going (bonus if I can achieve GPU passthrough) rofi emoji switcher is it possible to rice systemd-boot? the answer is no 😥 neovim needs more of your attention background manga setup with hakuneko + zathura or mangodl with ranger backup files on the hard disk and make it btrfs! updated: no, going with ext4 vimwiki as git home zathura rice discord rice spotify rice migrate from wal to wpgtk i3 stuff:  i3-notifier i3-resurrect i3-bar as a hidden status line make a theme randomizer/chooser with rofi make a rofi cheatsheet (I&amp;rsquo;m too alpha for this) floating vim everywhere 😵 thread   configure broot transfer dotfiles to one folder and symlink everything git dotfiles + reddit post?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
